<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Evolutionary Strategies - Tag - Corentin LEGER</title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/evolutionary-strategies/</link>
        <description>Evolutionary Strategies - Tag - Corentin LEGER</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/evolutionary-strategies/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Research: Evolving Reservoirs for Meta Reinforcement Learning (EvoStar 2024)</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/er_mrl/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Corentin Léger*, Gautier Hamon*, Eleni Nisioti, Xavier Hinaut, Clément Moulin-Frier</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/er_mrl/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Paper presented at EvoStar 2024 (Long Talk).
Abstract Animals often demonstrate a remarkable ability to adapt to their environments during their lifetime. They do so partly due to the evolution of morphological and neural structures. These structures capture features of environments shared between generations to bias and speed up lifetime learning.
In this work, we propose a computational model for studying a mechanism that can enable such a process. We adopt a computational framework based on meta reinforcement learning as a model of the interplay between evolution and development.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Hackathon: Ebiose</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/ebiose/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Corentin</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/ebiose/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Participated to a project called Ebiose during a 2 days hackathon with a team of 4 people. It focuses on a multi-language-based-agent system to solve tasks. In this system, agents are composed of LLM (e.g. GPT-3.5) coupled with a specific prompt. The structure of the multi-agent system followes a predetermined sequence, where one agent answers a question, another verifies the answer, and a final agent synthesizes both responses. This collaboration is inspired by the Autogen Framework, emphasizing coordinated efforts among agents.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
