<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#39;Cognitique&#39; Engineer on Corentin LEGER</title>
    <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#39;Cognitique&#39; Engineer on Corentin LEGER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://corentinlger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alzheimer disease detection by 3D MRI analysis </title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/alzheimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/alzheimer/</guid>
      <description>This project focuses on medical imaging. The goal is to develop a method in order to detect the state of development of Alzheimer disease thanks 3D MRI scans of humain brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symbolic Reinforcement learning - Research project with Inria</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/symbolicrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/symbolicrl/</guid>
      <description>Modeling complex problems is a real issue in Reinforcement learning. The goal of this projet is to use a RL model, such as Q-learning, on symbolic data, where the knowledge of the problem would be stored, in the form of qualitative or numerical data (in JSON for example). Instead of only working with numerical data, we could link the data with a certain &amp;rsquo;edition distance&amp;rsquo; which permits to evaluate the proximity of 2 elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotion classifier</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/emotionclassifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/emotionclassifier/</guid>
      <description>This data science project aims to identify what emotion a person is feeling on a picture. Here, we especially focus on depressed or happy people. In order to do so, pictures were downloaded from the web thanks to a data pipeline and have then been pre-processed. Then, a deep learning model has been created with Tensorflow in order to classify emotions of people. The model has finally been evaluated, and tested on other random images and gave excellent results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaceship Titanic</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/spacetitanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/spacetitanic/</guid>
      <description>This is a kaggle data science project wich aims to discover who was in the &amp;lsquo;Spaceship Titanic&amp;rsquo;, an interstellar passenger liner. We used an ensemble learning algorithm to achieve this goal : a random forest. After a step of pre-processing with missing values prediction (with a KNN algotithm for numerical values), our machine learning model was able to identify wether a person was in the ship or not with an accuracy of about 80%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance optimization for an helicopter fleet</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/connectivit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/connectivit/</guid>
      <description>This is my first internship in data science for Connectiv-IT. My mission was to work on the optimization of the maintenance of an aircraft fleet. I realized several data science tasks such as data processing and visualization, but also statistical analysis and clustering thanks to unsupervised learning. Two models of outlier detection and missing value simulation were also created, as well as a theoretical linear programming optimization model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Elections</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/elections/</guid>
      <description>This is the first big data (and data science) project I ever made, during my scholarship in Canada. The goal of this project is to predict the vote of canadian citizens during the 2019 election, thanks to responses to a survey. Despite the fact that we were beginners in this field,we managed with my classmate to predict about 80% of those votes right. Link to Github repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a mobile application &#39;Baroudeurs&#39;</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/baroudeur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/baroudeur/</guid>
      <description>This is a transdisciplinary project that ended up with the creation of a mobile application called “Baroudeurs”. The goal is to help people discover cities in a innovative manner. Indeed, Baroudeurs doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you a particular itinerary to places or monuments, but it lets you discover a city and its misteries. The idea is to get inspiration from video games to devellop the application, to create an experience based on discovery, curiosity the amazement to find a new places and learn its history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-machine interface for Ice cream shop</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/ihmcanada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/ihmcanada/</guid>
      <description>This UX project was realized with 5 other classmates in Canada. We had to create a brand new human machine interface for an ice cream shop and answer to specific needs. In order to do so, we had to contact potential customers but also people working in this fiel, and interview them based on UX methods. When we fully understood the needs of the future interface users, we started to create wireframes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress and addiction </title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/stressaddiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/stressaddiction/</guid>
      <description>This is a neuroscience and psychology project that aims to understand the relation between two phenomenons : stress and addiction. The article written will in a first time explain some parts of stress mecanism, then addiction and finally how they interact with each other.
Link to the article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a 22 years old student who is passionate about human, science and sport! After high-school, I went two years in preparatory class in Bordeaux, in sport study program in volley-ball. I still play in french national 3 league in Talence with friends.
After this, I joined the engineering school ENSC (Ecole Nationale Supérieure de Cognitique) . Cognitique is a french word designating the association between cognitive and computer sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact me on social medias :
LinkedIn : link here email : coleger@ensc.fr </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
