<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Corentin LEGER</title>
    <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Corentin LEGER</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://corentinlger.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emotion classifier</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/emotionclassifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/emotionclassifier/</guid>
      <description>This data science project that aims to identify what emotion a person is living on a picture. Here, we especially focus on depressed or happy people. In order to do so, pictures were downloaded from the web thanks to a data pipeline and have then been pre-processed. Then, a machine learning model has been created with the Tensorflow package to learn our artificial intelligence what people look like depending on their emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaceship Titanic</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/spacetitanic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/spacetitanic/</guid>
      <description>This is a kaggle data science project wich aims to discover who was in the &amp;lsquo;Spaceship Titanic&amp;rsquo;, an interstellar passenger liner. We used an ensemble learning algorithm to achieve this goal : a random forest. After a step of pre-processing with missing values prediction (with a KNN algotithm for numerical values), our machine learning model was able to identify wether a person was in the ship or not with an accuracy of about 80%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance optimization for an helicopter fleet</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/connectivit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/connectivit/</guid>
      <description>This is my first internship in data science for Connectiv-IT. My mission was to work on the optimization of the maintenance of an aircraft fleet. I realized several data science tasks such as data processing and visualization, but also statistical analysis and clustering thanks to unsupervised learning. Two models of outlier detection and missing value simulation were also created, as well as a theoretical linear programming optimization model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CartPole-v0 Reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/cartpole-v0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/cartpole-v0/</guid>
      <description>A classical reinforcement learning project on the gym environment CartPole-V0. The agent is the cart, controlled by two possible actions +1, -1 pointing on moving left or right. Our goal is to maintain this cart as straight as possible. To do so, we developped two reinforcement learning models, using Proximal Policy Optimization (PPO) and Deep Q-Network (DQN) methods.
Link to Github repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather predict</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/weatherpredict/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/weatherpredict/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple data science project to predict weather thanks to historical data, using the python librairy NeuralProphet, which is used for modeling time-series data based on neural networks. More precisely, we made an estimation of the temparature of Melbourne for each day between 2015 and 2016. Then we saved our model with pickle librairy. Link to Github repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Elections</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/elections/</guid>
      <description>This is the first big data (and data science) project I ever made, during my scholarship in Canada. The goal of this project is to predict the vote of canadian citizens during the 2019 election, thanks to responses to a survey. Despite the fact that we were beginners in this field,we managed with my classmate to predict about 80% of those votes right. Link to Github repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a mobile application &#39;Baroudeurs&#39;</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/baroudeur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/baroudeur/</guid>
      <description>This is a transdisciplinary project that ended up with the creation of a mobile application called “Baroudeurs”. The goal is to help people discover cities in a innovative manner. Indeed, Baroudeurs doesn&amp;rsquo;t give you a particular itinerary to places or monuments, but it lets you discover a city and its misteries. The idea is to get inspiration from video games to devellop the application, to create an experience based on discovery, curiosity the amazement to find a new places and learn its history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graph Traversal</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/graph-traversal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/graph-traversal/</guid>
      <description>This is our first artificial intellligence project with two classmates at the ENSC. The goal was to use graph traversal algorithms such as Diksjtra or A* to find the shortest path to a location on a map. In order to do so, we had to adapt to each environment to find appropriate heuristics and improve our algorithms.
Link to Github repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-machine interface for Ice cream shop</title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/ihmcanada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/ihmcanada/</guid>
      <description>This UX project was realized with 5 other classmates in Canada. We had to create a brand new human machine interface for an ice cream shop and answer to specific needs. In order to do so, we had to contact potential customers but also people working in this fiel, and interview them based on UX methods. When we fully understood the needs of the future interface users, we started to create wireframes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stress and addiction </title>
      <link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/stressaddiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/stressaddiction/</guid>
      <description>This is a neuroscience and psychology project that aims to understand the relation between two phenomenons : stress and addiction. The article written will in a first time explain some parts of stress mecanism, then addiction and finally how they interact with each other.
Link to the article</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
