<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science on Corentin LEGER</title><link>https://corentinlger.github.io/tags/data-science/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science on Corentin LEGER</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://corentinlger.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emotion classifier</title><link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/emotionclassifier/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/emotionclassifier/</guid><description>This data science project aims to identify what emotion a person is feeling on a picture. Here, we especially focus on depressed or happy people. In order to do so, pictures were downloaded from the web thanks to a data pipeline and have then been pre-processed. Then, a deep learning model has been created with Tensorflow in order to classify emotions of people. The model has finally been evaluated, and tested on other random images and gave excellent results.</description></item><item><title>Spaceship Titanic</title><link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/spacetitanic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/spacetitanic/</guid><description>This is a kaggle data science project wich aims to discover who was in the &amp;lsquo;Spaceship Titanic&amp;rsquo;, an interstellar passenger liner. We used an ensemble learning algorithm to achieve this goal : a random forest. After a step of pre-processing with missing values prediction (with a KNN algotithm for numerical values), our machine learning model was able to identify wether a person was in the ship or not with an accuracy of about 80%.</description></item><item><title>Maintenance optimization for an helicopter fleet</title><link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/connectivit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/connectivit/</guid><description>This is my first internship in data science for Connectiv-IT. My mission was to work on the optimization of the maintenance of an aircraft fleet. I realized several data science tasks such as data processing and visualization, but also statistical analysis and clustering thanks to unsupervised learning. Two models of outlier detection and missing value simulation were also created, as well as a theoretical linear programming optimization model.</description></item><item><title>Canadian Elections</title><link>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/elections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://corentinlger.github.io/post/elections/</guid><description>This is the first big data (and data science) project I ever made, during my scholarship in Canada. The goal of this project is to predict the vote of canadian citizens during the 2019 election, thanks to responses to a survey. Despite the fact that we were beginners in this field,we managed with my classmate to predict about 80% of those votes right. Link to Github repository</description></item></channel></rss>