<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Deep Learning - Tag - Corentin LEGER</title>
        <link>http://example.org/tags/deep-learning/</link>
        <description>Deep Learning - Tag - Corentin LEGER</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/deep-learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Software: Parallelization computation tutorial</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/parallezliationtutorial/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Corentin</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/parallezliationtutorial/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Created an open source turorial for hyper parameter search using Optuna for the ReservoirPy machine learning library.
First, it explains how to search hyper parameters on your machine sequentially, but also in a parallelized manner using the joblib library. Then, it demonsrates how to perform the same search at a larger scale, by using slurm files to parallelize it on a remote cluster of CPUs.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Rising Sun</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/risingsun/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Corentin</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/risingsun/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[To try to beat friends on the combat phases of the &ldquo;Rising Sun&rdquo; board game, I created this simplified gymnasium implementation of the game. The project also incorporates a python script to train a single RL agent on the environment. This agent can currently only be trained against hard-coded players (either random of with heuristics).
The next step will be to add multi-agents training to the project. Then, it will be interesting to explore the path of self play to see how complex the behaviors of the agent can become !]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Alzheimer disease detection by 3D MRI analysis </title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/alzheimer/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Corentin</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/posts/alzheimer/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This project focuses on medical imaging and computer vision. The goal is to develop a machine learning model able to detect the state of development of the Alzheimer disease, using 3D MRI data from real patients. In order to do so, we tried different approaches, including the &lsquo;2D epsilon&rsquo; method, which is the use of 2D Convolutionnal neural networks on 2D slices of the MRI, and also the use of 3D CNN.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
